<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ContextHelp version="0.5" Author="Kurtnoise" LastUpdated="20-06-08">
	<Codec name="x264">
		<!--To Do List: 
1 Use info from x264 help  -  DONE
2: Use info from MeGUI  - No Info Here
3: Begin Doom9 perusal (x264 GUIDE) - DONE
4: Begin Doom9 perusal (forum) - commencing
4: Clear up remaining with Devs
-->
		<!--Frame type options:-->
		<keyint name="Maximum Key Frame Interval">
			<Advanced>
Defines the maximum size of a Group of Pictures. A frame in a GOP cannot reference
frames in other GOPs, and in doing so enables seeking and random access. GOP sizes
are dynamically calculated during encoding to maximise compression, however specifying
a maximum GOP prevents any reduction of seekability.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Maximum GOP size</Basic>
			<Recommended>250</Recommended>
			<Default>250</Default>
		</keyint>
		<min-keyint name="Minimum Key Frame Interval">
			<Advanced>
Defines the minimum size of a Group of Pictures. A frame in a GOP cannot reference
frames in other GOPs, and in doing so enables seeking and random access.
GOP sizes are dynamically calculated during encoding to maximise compression,
however specifying a minimum GOP will help improve compression in high motion scenes.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Minimum GOP size</Basic>
			<Recommended>25</Recommended>
			<Default>25</Default>
		</min-keyint>
		<scenecut name="Scene Change Sensitivity">
			<Advanced>
Modifies the sensitivity to scene changes. Scene change detection is useful as it forces
the use of an I-frame at a scene change, leading to better looking cuts and overall
improvement in quality.</Advanced>
			<Basic>How aggressively scene changes are detected</Basic>
			<Recommended>40</Recommended>
			<Default>40</Default>
		</scenecut>
		<bframes name="Maximum B-frames">
			<Advanced>
Bi-directional Predictive Frames are highly compressed as they only store the data that
has changed from the previous frame or that is different from the next frame. B-frames
generally have less quality than I- or P- frames but can increase the overall quality of the
video by storing data very efficiently. A setting of 2 to 3 will usually provide a good
overall quality while allowing significant compression advantages.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Maximum number of B-frames between I and P frames</Basic>
			<Recommended>2 to 3</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</bframes>
		<b-adapt name="Adaptive B-frames">
			<Advanced>
Enables x264 to make adaptive decisions on where B-frames should be used, decreasing
the number of consecutive B-frames where it makes sense.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Enables adaptive B-frame decisions</Basic>
			<Recommended>1 - Fast</Recommended>
			<Default>1 - Fast</Default>
		</b-adapt>
		<b-bias name="B-frame Bias">
			<Advanced>
Positive values increase the likelihood that a B-frame will be used, negative values decrease
the likelihood, without violating the "Maximum B-frames" setting.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Influences how often B-frames are used</Basic>
			<Recommended>0</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</b-bias>
		<b-pyramid name="B-frame Pyramid">
			<Advanced>
Allows B-frames to be used as references for other B-frames, increasing compression efficiency
when 2 or more B-frames are used.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Keep some B-frames as references</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</b-pyramid>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<no-cabac name="Encode CABAC">
			<Advanced>
CABAC is a clever technique of losslessly compressing the syntax elements of the video
stream, knowing the probabilities of the elements in a given context. CABAC uses more
CPU for encoding and decoding. When disabled, video is encoded using CAVLC (Context
Adaptive Variable Length Encoding) which is less CPU intensive but provides less compression.
Note: Some advanced features will not be available when encoding with CAVLC.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Encode with Context Adaptive Binary Arithmetic Coding to increase compression</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</no-cabac>
		<ref name="Reference Frames">
			<Advanced>
Determines how many previous frames can be referenced by a P- or B-frame. Encoding slows
as more frames are used. The maximum value is 16, however quality increases become marginal
with more than 5 reference frames.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Number of reference frames</Basic>
			<Recommended>1 to 5</Recommended>
			<Default>1</Default>
		</ref>
		<nf name="Deblocking (in loop) Filter">
			<Advanced>
MPEG-4 AVC defines video with a grid of squares representing moving data, the in loop deblocking
filter detects the edges of these squares in order to smooth them. In loop deblocking is part of the
normal operation of MPEG-4 AVC and should not be disabled.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Disable deblocking (in loop) filter</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</nf>
		<filter name="Deblocking (in loop) Filter Strength">
			<Advanced>
Deblocking strength is computed for each macroblock according to the quantizer of the macroblock
and that of its neighbours. Alpha is used to determine whether the frontier of an encoded macroblock
is blocky or if it's actually a detail. It works like a threshold. Beta also works like a threshold, but is
used to insure that the picture is homogenous on both sides of the frontier in order to separate detail
from blockiness. When blocks are detected, alpha is used to decide the strength (maximum allowed
modification of the pixel). Beta applies slight modification to this strength if the macroblock is homogenous. </Advanced>
			<Basic>
Deblocking Strength : Deblocking Threshold (strength : threshold). The Deblocking Threshold
determines how easily the filter detects blocks. The Deblocking Strength determines how strong
detected blocks should be deblocked. The default provides an accurate mix of deblocking while
preserving detail. Adjustments should range from -3 to 3 (lower values indicate less deblocking.
Negative values do not indicate the deblocking effect is reversed). Note: Setting values too high
will result in loss of detail and texture or smearing. Setting the value to low may leave sharp edges
or mosquito noise. There should be a positive correlation between each setting, ie. if you apply
heavier deblocking, you should increase the threshold so that more data is deblocked.</Basic>
			<Recommended>0:0</Recommended>
			<Default>0:0</Default>
		</filter>
		<!--Rate control options:-->
		<qp name="Constant Quantizer">
			<Advanced>
In Constant Quantizer mode, each frame is encoded with the same mathematical quality
(or quantizer) as every other frame, regardless of the bit rate required to do so, applying
a constant mathematical quality to the entire video sequence. Lower values indicate lower
compression (higher quality). There is no way to predict file size in this mode. Note: Values
under 15 are only useful for archival/reproduction quality and values over 40 show considerable
loss in quality.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Encode in Constant Quality mode (0 = lossless) regardless of bit rate. Note: This mode only requires 1 pass.</Basic>
			<Recommended>24 to 28</Recommended>
			<Default>26</Default>
		</qp>
		<bitrate name="Average Bit Rate">
			<Advanced>
In Average (Variable) Bit Rate mode (VBR), each frame is encoded at the lowest possible
quantizer (best quality) while maintaining the average bit rate specified over time. File size
can be predicted in this mode. Note: Other VBV settings determine the level of change in
local bit rate used to compensate for changing scene complexity.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Sets the average bit rate that the file is to be encoded in. Note: this mode performs best in 2 passes.</Basic>
			<Recommended>N/A</Recommended>
			<Default>N/A</Default>
		</bitrate>
		<crf name="Quality Based VBR">
			<Advanced>
In Constant Quality Based VBR mode, each frame is encoded with almost the same mathematical
quality (or quantizer) as every other frame, taking motion (rate control) into account. This mode
improves visual quality by encoding high motion scenes with slightly higher compression (lower
quality) and  low motion scenes with slightly lower compression (higher quality). While the quantizer
(mathematical quality) may fluctuate over time, less bits are spent on scenes where high speed fine
detail would be invisible, and more bits are spent in scenes where more static fine detail is more visible.
This applies a constant visual quality to the entire video sequence. Lower values indicate lower
compression (higher quality). There is no way to predict file size in this mode. Note: Values under
15 are only useful for archival/reproduction quality and values over 40 show considerable loss in
quality. This mode is only tuned for qcomp=0.6.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Encode in Quality Based Variable Bit Rate mode, regardless of bit rate. Note: This mode can perform best in 2 passes.</Basic>
			<Recommended>24 to 28</Recommended>
			<Default>26</Default>
		</crf>
		<qpmin name="Minimum Quantizer">
			<Advanced>
Enforces a minimum Quantizer. Prevents the codec from outputting frames with too little
compression, wasting bits. Note: This is disregarded in Constant Quality or Quality Based VBR modes.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Set minimum Quantizer factor.</Basic>
			<Recommended>10</Recommended>
			<Default>10</Default>
		</qpmin>
		<qpmax name="Maximum Quantizer">
			<Advanced>
Enforces a maximum Quantizer. Prevents the codec from outputting frames with too much compression,
causing reduced quality. Note: This is disregarded in Constant Quality or Quality Based VBR modes.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Set maximum Quantizer factor.</Basic>
			<Recommended>51</Recommended>
			<Default>51</Default>
		</qpmax>
		<qpstep name="Maximum Quantizer Steps">
			<Advanced>
Sets how much the quantizer can change between consecutive frames, maintaining a more stable
level of quality.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Set maximum quantizer step.</Basic>
			<Recommended>4</Recommended>
			<Default>4</Default>
		</qpstep>
		<ratetol name="Average Bit rate Variance (%)">
			<Advanced>
Regulates how much the bit rate can fluctuate from the target Average Bit Rate that has
been set. Lower settings constrict bit rate changes, producing a file that will stream better
and more closely match a predicted file size based on the set bit rate, while reducing the
codec's ability to adapt to complex scenes. Higher settings increase bit rate variability which
decreases the reliability of streaming and the ability to predict the file size, while improving
the codec's ability to adapt to complex scenes. Setting this to 0% would result in a constant
bit rate. Setting this to 100% would provide a highly erratic bit rate dependant on scene
complexity. (A setting of 100% would result in Constant Quantizer compression.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Allowed variance of average bit rate. Lower values indicate less variance, while higher values indicate more variance.</Basic>
			<Recommended>1.0 to 4.0</Recommended>
			<Default>1.0</Default>
		</ratetol>
		<vbv-maxrate name="VBV Maximum Bit rate">
			<Advanced>
Specifies the maximum bit rate allowed in the Video Buffer.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Max local bit rate of Video Buffer Verifier.</Basic>
			<Recommended>0 (Automatic)</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</vbv-maxrate>
		<vbv-bufsize name="VBV Buffer Size">
			<Advanced>
Specifies the maximum size of the Video Buffer, which can affect playback start up times
if too large and cause stuttering if too small.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Size of Video Buffer Verifier.</Basic>
			<Recommended>0 (Automatic)</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</vbv-bufsize>
		<vbv-init name="VBV Initial Size">
			<Advanced>
Specifies the level of the Video Buffer to fill before playback can begin. Low levels may
cause reduced initial quality while high levels may cause artificially high initial quality.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Initial Video Buffer Verifier occupancy.</Basic>
			<Recommended>0.9</Recommended>
			<Default>0.9</Default>
		</vbv-init>
		<ipratio name="I-P Quantizer Factor">
			<Advanced>
Specifies the level of quality reduction between high quality I-frames and the more
compressed P-frames that follow.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Quantization factor used between I- and P-frames.</Basic>
			<Recommended>1.4</Recommended>
			<Default>1.4</Default>
		</ipratio>
		<pbratio name="P-B Quantizer Factor">
			<Advanced>
Specifies the level of quality reduction between P-frames and the more compressed B-frames that follow.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Quantization factor between P- and B-frames.</Basic>
			<Recommended>1.3</Recommended>
			<Default>1.3</Default>
		</pbratio>
		<chroma-qp-offset name="Chroma and Luma Quantizer Offset">
			<Advanced>
Specifies the level of quality reduction between colour and brightness information.
The human eye is more sensitive to changes in brightness than colour, so compression
can be increased by removing some colour detail.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Quantization difference between chroma (colour) and luma (brightness) values.</Basic>
			<Recommended>0</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</chroma-qp-offset>
		<pass name="Multipass Mode">
			<Advanced>
Multiple passes allow the codec to make more informed choices when deciding how
to compress each frame in  regards to the quality and complexity of the entire clip.
Note: 2 pass encoding will take up to twice as long.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Enable multipass rate control for Average Bit Rate or Quality based VBR modes.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</pass>
		<stats name="Statistics File Name">
			<Advanced>
This file holds information generated about each frame, which is then used to make
more informed choices on the finial pass.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Filename for multipass statistics</Basic>
			<Recommended>x264_2pass.log</Recommended>
			<Default>x264_2pass.log</Default>
		</stats>
		<qcomp name="Quantizer Curve Compression">
			<Advanced>
Regulates how much the quality can fluctuate within the target Average Bit Rate that
has been set. Higher settings constrict quality changes, producing a file that will have
a more constant quality throughout, while reducing the codec's ability to adapt to complex
scenes where loss of detail may not be as important. Lower settings increase variability
of quality, which may improve visual quality throughout the video by reducing quality
where fine detail can't be seen and increasing it where fine detail is more noticeable.
Setting this to 1 would result in constant quality. Setting this to 0 would create highly
erratic quality changes.</Advanced>
			<Basic>
Allowed variance of average quantizer (or quality). Higher values indicate less variance,
while lower values indicate more variance. Note: 1 indicates constant quality while 0
indicates maximum fluctuation.</Basic>
			<Recommended>0.60</Recommended>
			<Default>0.60</Default>
		</qcomp>
		<cplxblur name="Quantizer Fluctuation Reduction (Before)">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Reduce fluctuations in Quantizer (before curve compression).</Basic>
			<Recommended>20.0</Recommended>
			<Default>20.0</Default>
		</cplxblur>
		<qblur name="Quantizer Fluctuation Reduction (After)">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Reduce fluctuations in QP (after curve compression).</Basic>
			<Recommended>0.5</Recommended>
			<Default>0.5</Default>
		</qblur>
		<zones name="Define Zones">
			<Advanced>
Zones allow you to define areas of video for which you can specify additional encoding
options. eg you may specify the credits at the end of the film to use a lower bit rate or
higher compression than the main feature.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Define regions of video for which additional encoding options can be specified.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</zones>
		<!--Analysis options:-->
		<analyse name="Macroblock Analysis Sizes">
			<Advanced>
Enabling additional macroblock search sizes increases encoding efficiency and quality
but decreases speed. Note: i8x8 can only be used in High Profile and when Adaptive
8x8 DCT is used.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Specify which Macroblock Partition Sizes to analyse</Basic>
			<Recommended>All (High Profile)</Recommended>
			<Default>p8x8,b8x8,i8x8,i4x4</Default>
		</analyse>
		<direct name="B-frame Mode">
			<Advanced>
Determines how motion vectors for B-frames are derived. Spatial uses neighbouring
blocks in the same frame which may result in higher PSNR. Temporal makes use of
neighbouring frames which may be perceived as higher quality. Auto selects direct
mode per frame. Works best in 2pass (enable in both passes).</Advanced>
			<Basic>Direct motion vector prediction mode</Basic>
			<Recommended>Spatial</Recommended>
			<Default>Spatial</Default>
		</direct>
		<weightb name="B-frame Weighted Prediction">
			<Advanced>
Enables 'brightness' weighting of B-frames which improves fades and colour gradients ie sky.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Weighted prediction for B-frames</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</weightb>
		<me name="Motion Estimation Mode">
			<Advanced>
Controls the method used to search for motion vectors. Diamond search radius 1 (fastest),
 hexagonal search radius 2 (fast), uneven multi-hexagon search (slow), exhaustive search
(slowest). Exhaustive search is not recommended for normal use as it is exceptionally slow
and does not provide significant quality increases.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Motion estimation method: 1=fast, 4=best</Basic>
			<Recommended>hexagonal</Recommended>
			<Default>hexagonal</Default>
		</me>
		<merange name="Maximum Motion Vector Range">
			<Advanced>
Specifies the maximum range a macroblock can travel in order to be encoded as a vector.
Larger values may increase efficiency but will increase encoding time.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Maximum motion vector search range.</Basic>
			<Recommended>16 to 32</Recommended>
			<Default>16</Default>
		</merange>
		<subme name="Sub Pixel Refinement">
			<Advanced>
Controls the decision quality of motion estimation. Lower values will make faster and less
accurate decisions. Higher values will improve quality but will slow encoding speed.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Sub Pixel motion estimation and partition decision quality: 1=fast, 9=best.</Basic>
			<Recommended>6</Recommended>
			<Default>6</Default>
		</subme>
		<mixed-refs name="Mixed References">
			<Advanced>
Allows each 8x8 or 16x8 partition in a macroblock to independently select a reference frame,
as opposed to only one reference frame per macroblock.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Decide references on a per partition basis</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</mixed-refs>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<no-chroma-me name="Chroma Motion Estimation">
			<Advanced>
Enables Motion Estimation to take colour components of the video into account when calculating movement, improving quality.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Use chroma in motion estimation</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Enabled</Default>
		</no-chroma-me>
		<!--Note: name changed from 8x8dct due to invalid XML character warning-->
		<i8x8dct name="Adaptive 8x8 DCT">
			<Advanced>
Enables the intelligent adaptive use of 8x8 transforms in I-frames. Requires I8X8 checked.
      </Advanced>
			<Basic>Adaptive spatial transform size</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</i8x8dct>
    <i4x4mv name="4x4 sub-partitions for I-Frames">
      <Advanced>
Enables the use of 4x4 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for I-frames.</Advanced>
      <Basic>4x4 sub-partitions for I-Frames</Basic>
      <Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
      <Default>Disabled</Default>
    </i4x4mv>
    <p4x4mv name="4x4 sub-partitions for P-Frames">
      <Advanced>
Enables the use of 4x4 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for P-frames. 
Improves compression by about 0.5%, at the cost of encoding speed. Requires P8X8 enabled.</Advanced>
      <Basic>4x4 sub-partitions for P-Frames</Basic>
      <Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
      <Default>Disabled</Default>
    </p4x4mv>
    <p8x8mv name="8x8 sub-partitions for P-Frames">
      <Advanced>
Enables the use of 8x8 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for P-frames.</Advanced>
      <Basic>8x8 sub-partitions for P-Frames</Basic>
      <Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
      <Default>Disabled</Default>
    </p8x8mv>
    <b8x8mv name="8x8 sub-partitions for B-Frames">
      <Advanced>
Enables the use of 8x8 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for B-frames.</Advanced>
      <Basic>8x8 sub-partitions for B-Frames</Basic>
      <Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
      <Default>Disabled</Default>
    </b8x8mv>
    <i8x8mv name="8x8 sub-partitions for I-Frames">
      <Advanced>
Enables the use of 8x8 sub-partitions in predicted macroblocks, for I-frames.</Advanced>
      <Basic>8x8 sub-partitions for I-Frames</Basic>
      <Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
      <Default>Disabled</Default>
    </i8x8mv>
		<trellis name="Trellis Quantization">
			<Advanced>
Performs Trellis quantization to increase efficiency. On Macroblock provides a
good compromise between speed and efficiency. On all decisions reduces
speed further.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Trellis Rate Distortion quantization. (Requires CABAC, disables deadzone)</Basic>
			<Recommended>On Macro Block</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</trellis>
		<psyrd name="Psychovisual RD optimizations">
			<Advanced>
Modifies the rate-distortion metric to improve sharpness and detail retention.
			</Advanced>
			<Basic>Improves detail retention</Basic>
			<Recommended>1.0</Recommended>
			<Default>1.0</Default>
		</psyrd>
		<psytrellis name="Psychovisual Trellis optimizations">
			<Advanced>
Experimental: attempts to improve sharpness beyond that of the ordinary trellis algorithm.
Your mileage may vary.			
			</Advanced>
			<Basic>Experimental modification to trellis.</Basic>
			<Recommended>0.0</Recommended>
			<Default>0.0</Default>
		</psytrellis>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<no-fast-pskip name="Fast P-frame Skip Detection">
			<Advanced>
Fast Skip detection increases speed but may cause slight blockiness in areas
of solid colour or slight gradients such as dark scenes or sky.
Enabling this option will DISABLE the Fast Skip detection.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Disables early Skip detection on P-frames.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</no-fast-pskip>
		<nr name="Noise Reduction">
			<Advanced>
Estimates film noise based on this value and attempts to remove it by
dropping small details before quantization. This may not match the quality
of a good external noise reduction filter, but it performs very fast.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Performs fast noise reduction.</Basic>
			<Recommended>0 (100-1000 for denoising)</Recommended>
			<Default>0</Default>
		</nr>
		<cqm name="Preset Quantization Matrices">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Preset quantization matrices. (jvt, flat)</Basic>
			<Recommended>Flat</Recommended>
			<Default>Flat</Default>
		</cqm>
		<cqmfile name="Quantization Matrice File">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Read quantization matrices from a JM compatible file. (Overrides any other --cqm* options).</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</cqmfile>
		<cqm4 name="4x4 Quantization Matrices">
			<Advanced>
Takes a comma separated list of 16 integers.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Set all 4x4 quantization matrices.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</cqm4>
		<cqm8 name="8x8 Quantization Matrices">
			<Advanced>
Takes a comma separated list of 64 integers.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Set all 8x8 quantization matrices.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</cqm8>
		<!-- Not Documented: 
	cqm4i, cqm4p, cqm8i, cqm8p: Set both luma and chroma quant matrices
	cqm4iy, cqm4ic, cqm4py, cqm4pc: Set individual quant matrices-->
		<!--Video Usability options:
Note: these settings are not used by the encoder but are suggestions to the playback equipment-->
		<sar name="Sample Aspect Ratio">
			<Advanced>
Stores the size of non-square pixels in the video stream for use during playback. This enables anamorphic video.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Specify Sample Aspect Ratio</Basic>
			<Recommended>1:1</Recommended>
			<Default>1:1</Default>
		</sar>
		<!-- Not Documented:
      overscan <string>     Specify crop overscan setting ["undef"]
                                  - undef, show, crop
      videoformat <string>  Specify video format ["undef"]
                                  - component, pal, ntsc, secam, mac, undef
      fullrange <string>    Specify full range samples setting ["off"]
                                  - off, on
      colorprim <string>    Specify color primaries ["undef"]
                                  - undef, bt709, bt470m, bt470bg
                                    smpte170m, smpte240m, film
      transfer <string>     Specify transfer characteristics ["undef"]
                                  - undef, bt709, bt470m, bt470bg, linear,
                                    log100, log316, smpte170m, smpte240m
      colormatrix <string>  Specify color matrix setting ["undef"]
                                  - undef, bt709, fcc, bt470bg
                                    smpte170m, smpte240m, GBR, YCgCo
      chromaloc <integer>   Specify chroma sample location (0 to 5) [0]
-->
		<!--Video Usability options:-->
		<level name="AVC Complexity Level">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Specify level (as defined by Annex A)</Basic>
			<Recommended>Unrestricted/AutGuess</Recommended>
			<Default>Unrestricted/AutoGuess</Default>
		</level>
		<fps name="Frame Rate">
			<Advanced>
This can be used to change the frame rate of the video during encoding
(or specify the frame rate for a source  that does not detect correctly).</Advanced>
			<Basic>Specify frame rate</Basic>
			<Recommended>Automatic</Recommended>
			<Default>Automatic</Default>
		</fps>
		<seek name="Seek to Start Frame">
			<Advanced>Enables encoding to begin at any point in the source.</Advanced>
			<Basic>First frame to encode</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</seek>
		<frames name="Frames to Encode">
			<Advanced>Enables encoding to finish at a point before the end of the source.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Maximum number of frames to encode</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</frames>
		<output name="Output File Name">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Specify output file</Basic>
			<Recommended></Recommended>
			<Default></Default>
		</output>
		<threads name="Number of Threads">
			<Advanced>
For optimum speed, this should be left at 0, ie automatic detection.
The automatic setting is 1.5 x logical CPUs. Threads increase encoding
speed and negligibly negatively affect quality.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Enable parallel encoding by using more than 1 thread to increase speed</Basic>
			<Recommended>0 (auto)</Recommended>
			<Default>0 (auto)</Default>
		</threads>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<no-asm name="CPU Optimizations">
			<Advanced>
Codecs use advanced CPU SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) instruction
sets allowing massive speed increases. This should only be enabled for
troubleshooting purposes.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Disable all CPU optimizations</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</no-asm>
		<!--WARNING DOUBLE NEGATIVE-->
		<psnr name="PSNR Computation">
			<Advanced>
Prevents PSNR calculations that are reported on completion.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Enable PSNR computation.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</psnr>
    <ssim name="SSIM Computation">
      <Advanced>
Prevents SSIM calculations that are reported on completion.</Advanced>
      <Basic>Enable SSIM computation</Basic>
      <Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
      <Default>Disabled</Default>
    </ssim>
    <losslessmode name="Lossless Mode">
      <Advanced>
Set QP to 0 to activate the lossless Mode.</Advanced>
      <Basic>Enable the lossless Mode</Basic>
      <Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
      <Default>Disabled</Default>
    </losslessmode>
    <fourcc name="The FourCC">
      <Advanced>
Specify the AVC FourCC you what you want. Depends mostly on the decoder used.</Advanced>
      <Basic>Specify the AVC FourCC</Basic>
      <Recommended>x264</Recommended>
      <Default>x264</Default>
    </fourcc>
		<quiet name="Quiet Mode">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Enable Quiet Mode (do not display output information).</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</quiet>
		<verbose name="Verbose Mode">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Show frame statistics.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</verbose>
		<progress name="Progress Meter">
			<Advanced></Advanced>
			<Basic>Show a progress indicator while encoding.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</progress>
		<visualize name="Visualize Analysis">
			<Advanced>
Debugging option used to understand what is happening on a frame by frame basis.</Advanced>
			<Basic>Show Macroblock types overlayed on the encoded video.</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</visualize>
		<aud name="Access Unit Delimiters">
			<Advanced>
Used for compatibility when using AVC in some transport streams (inc MPEG-2 TS).</Advanced>
			<Basic>Use access unit delimiters</Basic>
			<Recommended>Disabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</aud>
    <aqmode name="AQ Mode">
      <Advanced>
This option controls how AQ distributes bits. Mode 0 disables the feature whereas
Mode 1 enables Variance AQ (complexity mask).</Advanced>
      <Basic>The Mode of the Adaptive Quantizers</Basic>
      <Recommended>1</Recommended>
      <Default>1</Default>
    </aqmode>
    <aqstrength name="AQ Strength">
      <Advanced>
Reduces blocking and blurring in flat and textured areas. To have a weak AQ choose 0.5
and a strong one 1.5  as value.</Advanced>
      <Basic>Strength of the Adaptive Quantizers</Basic>
      <Recommended>1.0</Recommended>
      <Default>1.0</Default>
    </aqstrength>
    <profile name="AVC Profiles">
      <Advanced>
The H.264 standard includes the following sets of capabilities, which are referred to as profiles,
targeting specific classes of applications:
    - Baseline Profile (BP): Primarily for lower-cost applications with limited computing resources,
      this profile is used widely in videoconferencing and mobile applications.
    - Main Profile (MP): Originally intended as the mainstream consumer profile for broadcast and
      storage applications, the importance of this profile faded when the High profile was 
      developed for those applications.
    - Extended Profile (XP): Intended as the streaming video profile, this profile has relatively high
      compression capability and some extra tricks for robustness to data losses and server stream switching.
    - High Profile (HiP): The primary profile for broadcast and disc storage applications, particularly
      for high-definition television applications (this is the profile adopted into HD DVD and Blu-ray Disc,
      for example).
      </Advanced>
      <Basic>Choose your AVC Profile.</Basic>
      <Recommended>High Profile</Recommended>
      <Default>High Profile</Default>
    </profile>
	</Codec>
	<Codec name="Xvid">
		<setting1 name="setting1">
			<Advanced>Advanced Text</Advanced>
			<Basic>basic text</Basic>
			<Recommended>Enabled</Recommended>
			<Default>Disabled</Default>
		</setting1>
	</Codec>
  <Form name="PresetImporter">
    <presetList name="info">
      <Basic>To import all presets in once, right click on this list and select all...</Basic>
    </presetList>
  </Form>
  <Form name="PresetExporter">
    <presetList name="info">
      <Basic>To export all presets in once, right click on this list and select all...</Basic>
    </presetList>
  </Form>
</ContextHelp>
